Your very first princess summit.
You must be over the moon, Twilight.
I am excited. But, to be honest,
I'm a little nervous, too.
You're 'nervicited'!
It's like you wanna jump up and down
and yell "YAY ME!!"
But you also wanna curl up
in a teeny-tiny ball
and hide at the same time!
We've all been there!
I'm there almost every day.
You've got no reason to fret, Twi.
Everything's gonna be just–
TWILIGHT!
Oh, sorry, darling,
but I just realized
you're not wearing your crown.
You haven't forgotten it
back in Ponyville, have you?
It's in my bag.
Just feel a little self-conscious
about wearing it.
Haven't really gotten accustomed
to these yet, either.
You are a princess now, Twilight.
Embrace it!
I'm telling you,
if I had a crown like that,
I would never take it off.
Why, I'd sleep in the thing.
Her highness,
Princess Twilight Sparkle!
Twilight! I haven't seen you
since the coronation!
We have so much to discuss.
But it can wait until tomorrow.
You all look tired from your journey.
Now, off to bed, all of you.
What's wrong, Twilight?
I don't know, Spike.
I'm just... worried I guess.
Princess Cadance was given
the Crystal Empire to rule over.
What if, now that I'm a princess,
Celestia expects me
to lead a kingdom of my own?
That would be awesome!
No, it would not!
Just because I have this crown
and these wings, it doesn't mean
I'll be a good leader!
Aw, sure you will, Twilight.
Now come on,
you should get some shut-eye.
Big day tomorrow!
Can't... tuck...!
Just trying to get comfortable!
My Little Pony: Equestria Girls
(Spin Off Movie)
Subbed by GrayJeager
Fr.Jeager@Gmail.com
http://grayjeager.blogspot.fr
Huh? What?
My crown!
She's got my crown!
Stop! Thief!
She's stolen my crown!
Stop!
What did you do with my crown?
Sorry it had to be this way...
Princess!
Who was that?
Sunset Shimmer.
A former student of mine.
She began her studies with me
not long before Twilight.
But when she did not get what
she wanted as quickly as she liked,
she turned cruel and dishonest.
I tried to help her,
but she eventually decided to abandon
her studies and pursue her own path.
One that has sadly led her
to stealing your crown.
She replaced Twilight's
with this one.
I suppose Sunset Shimmer thought
you wouldn't notice right away
that this was not yours.
And by the time you did,
it would be too late to go after
your crown and Element of Harmony.
But I don't understand!
Where did she go?
Why did she take the crown?
You'll soon know more about
this place than even I do.
This is no ordinary mirror.
It is a gateway to another world.
A gateway that opens
once every thirty moons.
Sparkly!
It has always been kept in
the throne room of Canterlot Castle.
But when Princess Cadance
took over the Crystal Empire,
we sent it here
for her to watch over.
I had always hoped that Sunset Shimmer
would someday use it to return,
to come back to Equestria
seeking my guidance.
Obviously,
this is not what has happened.
Twilight,
you must use the mirror
to go into this other world
and retrieve your crown.
Without it, the other Elements
of Harmony have no power
and Equestria is left without one
of its most important means of defense.
Your crown does not belong in the place
Sunset Shimmer now calls home.
And in her possession,
your Element of Harmony
will no doubt be used to bring harm
to the inhabitants of this other realm.
They will not have the power
to defend themselves.
You understand
the importance of your task?
Of course.
Good. Then you must go at once.
She's going,
we're going with her!
Right, girls?
Ooooh! I'm so 'nervicited'!
You do realize that's not a real word,
right?
I'm afraid I can't let you go.
What?! Why not?!
Sending all of you could upset
the balance of this alternate world,
creating havoc
that would make it impossible
for Twilight to get the crown back
from Sunset Shimmer.
This is something
Princess Twilight must do alone.
Time is of the essence.
On the third day, when the moon
reaches its peak in the night sky,
the gateway will close.
And once it does,
it will be another thirty moons before
you will be able to use it to return.
- It's alright, Twi!
- You'll be back before you know it!
Spike, no!
Huh, Twilight?
Spike!
You're not supposed to...
Spike? Are you a...
dog?
I think so...
But I have no idea what you are!
Twilight,
you have to get it together!
What does the rest of me look like?
Um, like you. Only not you.
Your muzzle's really small.
My muzzle?!
Are you gonna scream again?
Where are we?
I don't know.
But that must serve
as the gateway back to Equestria.
We need to find my crown
as soon as possible and get back there.
I suggest we start searching
the castle first.
Works for me.
Yeah, I don't think that's how
the new you is supposed to–
Come on, Spike.
I do not wanna be like this
for longer than I have to.
Look on the bright side.
You don't have those pesky wings
to worry about anymore.
My magic! It isn't working!
Makes sense.
You don't exactly have your horn.
WHAT?!
We really need to find you a mirror.
What do you think, Spike?
Other artifacts she's stolen
from Equestria?
What am I?
You okay?
I don't think this is a castle.
I've never seen a place
that's quite like this
Everything is turned around
This crazy world is upside-down
Getting on my feet
it's the hand that I was dealt
But I don't have
much time with them
Got to learn all that I can
They don't use any magic
or fly with any wings
I don't get these funny clothes,
skinny legs or tiny nose
Everything's confusing
when it seems so new
But I look a little closer
and it starts to feel familiar too
What a strange new world
(what a strange new world)
I'm trying to make heads
or tails of this strange new world
Sorting through the small details
of this strange new world
What a strange new world
I'm really sorry.
I just found it, and I thought
I should give it to her.
I didn't know you had dropped it.
Well, I did!
And I was about to get it before
you swooped in and ruined everything!
You shouldn't pick up things
that don't belong to you.
It... doesn't really
belong to you, either.
Excuse me?!?
Nothing...
That's what I thought.
It's as good as mine, and you know it.
You really are pathetic.
It's no wonder your best friends
are all stray animals.
How dare you speak to her that way!
What did you say?
I said...
how dare you speak to her that way!
You must be new here.
I can speak to anyone any way I want.
I can't believe you did that!
I couldn't just stand there.
Well, it's just that nobody ever
stands up to Sunset Shimmer.
Sunset Shimmer?
- You've heard of her?
- Sort of...
I don't think
I've seen you around before.
Did you just transfer to Canterlot High
from another school?
Yes! Another... school!
My name's Twilight.
I'm... Fluttershy.
Sorry, what was that?
It's Fluttershy!
It sounds like you're saying Fluttershy,
but how can that...?
Oh, my goodness!
Who's this sweet little guy?
That's Spike! My, uh... dog!
Oh, he's so cute!
Go on, eat up, little pup!
Wouldn't you just give anything
to know what they're really thinking?
He usually just tells me.
Oh, what do you mean?
Oh, uh, nothing! Never mind.
Sunset Shimmer said
you picked something up.
Something that belonged to her.
It wasn't a crown, was it?
How did you know?
Uh, lucky guess?
Do you still have it?
But you know what happened to it.
This morning, I was passing out
flyers for the animal shelter
like I do every Wednesday.
Canterlot's animal shelter
needs more volunteers.
Won't you help an animal
that can't help itself?
I have no idea how it got there.
But I didn't want anything
to happen to it,
so I decided to give it
to Principal Celestia.
Principal Celestia?
She's the ruler here?
You could say that.
Technically, I guess she and
Vice Principal Luna do make the rules.
- Where is she now?
- Probably in her office.
Third door on your left.
Thank you!
Oh, wait!
You're not really supposed
to have pets on school grounds.
Might wanna tuck him
into your backpack.
That's what I do!
They just get so lonely
when I'm in school all day.
Oh, okay! Thank you!
Oh, no! I'm late for class!
Come in.
How may I help you?
My name's Twilight Sparkle.
I'm new here, and...
Well, I understand that Fluttershy found
a crown this morning and gave it to you.
Yes. I've had Vice Principal Luna
put it somewhere for safekeeping.
No idea how it ended up
in the front lawn.
Were you interested in running
for Princess of the Fall Formal this year?
Uh, no. Not exactly.
The truth is...
Well, the truth is I...
You see, the crown is actually...
Princess of the Fall Formal?
It's Canterlot High's big Fall dance.
- Like the Grand Galloping Gala!
- Grand Galloping Gala?
It was a big deal at my old school.
And was there a princess?
Yes, but she wasn't exactly a student.
Here at Canterlot High,
the students select one
of their peers to represent them.
She receives a crown
at the Fall Formal.
You asked me if I was interested
in running for Princess.
Can anyone run?
Yes. You just need to let the head
of the Fall Formal planning committee
know you'd like to be on the ballot.
Was there anything else?
Um, nope! That was it!
Well, if you do need anything else,
my door is always open.
Twilight, why didn't you just
tell her the crown was yours
- ...and ask for it back?
-  I was going to.
But imagine if one of them
showed up in Equestria
saying they came from a place
filled with tall,
fleshy, two-legged creatures
with these?
We'd think they were crazy!
Hmm. You make a good point.
Looks like if I want my crown back,
I'll have to become Princess
of the Canterlot High Fall Formal.
So that's what I'm gonna do!
And how exactly
do you plan on doing that?
I have no idea!
I know we've just met,
but I was wondering if you might
be able to help me with something.
Of course!
I've decided to run for
Princess of the Fall Formal, and–
Oh, gosh!
Sorry. It's just,
running for Fall Formal Princess
is a really bad idea.
Why?
Sunset Shimmer wants
to be Fall Formal Princess.
And when she wants something,
she gets it!
She'll make life awful for anyone
who stands in her way.
Just ask the girl who ran against her
for Princess of the Spring Fling.
I have to try!
I don't think you understand.
You'd have to convince everyone here
to vote for you instead of her.
The athletes.
The fashionistas.
The dramas.
The eco-kids.
The techies.
The rockers...
Why is everypony–
Everybody separated this way?
Maybe it was different
at your old school,
but at C.H.S.,
everybody sticks to their own kind.
One thing that they do have in common
is that they know Sunset Shimmer
is gonna rule the school until we graduate.
Not if I can help it!
So...
Where would I find the head
of the party planning committee?
Fluttershy said
she'd probably be in here.
Incoming!
Hi, my name's Twilight Sparkle and...
Pinkie Pie?
Are you psychic?!
Uh, no. I don't think so.
Unless of course that's something
you can do here.
Not usually.
Fluttershy said this is where
I'd find the head of the
Fall Formal planning committee.
Fluttershy, huh?
Don't let the whole "shy" thing fool you.
She can be a real meanie.
You two aren't friends?
Waited a bit to get your name
on the ballot, huh?
Dance is day after tomorrow.
I'm brand new here.
I thought you didn't look familiar.
Though, now that
I'm really lookin' at you...
Do you have a twin sister who lives
in the city, has a pet dog named Spike
that looks just like that one?
- Uh, maybe?
- Thought so.
Anywho, just need to fill this out
and you are officially up for the coveted
Princess of the Fall Formal crown.
You have really bad handwriting.
It's like you've never
held a pen before.
Is it?
Somebody order a dozen cases
of fizzy apple cider?
Oh! Oh! Me, me-me-me, me,
yeah, ha ha, me!
- Can you bring in the rest?
- Eeyup.
- Hey, I know you.
- You do?
Sure. You're the new girl who gave
Sunset Shimmer the what for today.
Twilight Sparkle here is going
to run against Sunset Shimmer
for Princess of the Fall Formal.
I'd think twice about that.
Oh, sure, she'll probably
approach you all friendly like...
"I sure am lookin' forward
to some friendly competition."
"That's so good to hear!"
But then,
here comes the backstabbin'.
About the only girl in this school
you can trust less than Sunset Shimmer
is Rainbow Dash.
Rainbow Dash?
She's the captain of, like,
every team at Canterlot High.
She's also the captain of sayin'
she's gonna do somethin' for ya,
and then turnin' around
and not even botherin' to show up.
Thanks for the advice, Applejack.
But this is something
I really need to do.
Suit yourself.
Hey, how'd you know
my name was Applejack?
- Didn't you say?
- Nope.
Well, it sure was sure nice
meeting you both.
I'm sure I'll be seeing you around.
That one's trying to hide a secret,
but I am totally on to her.
She's psychic!
If you say so.
This looks terrible!
There should be more streamers
near the stage and fewer balloons.
Yeah, streamers!
And fewer balloons!
Fizzy apple cider?
This is my coronation,
not a hoedown!
Well, now,
it ain't necessarily gonna be
your coronation this time around.
Oh, is that so?
You country folk
really aren't that bright.
Must be why the other students
say such awful things about you.
Obviously it's gonna be MY coronation.
I'm running unopposed.
Not this time.
The new girl just signed up!
What?!
I know.
Her handwriting is really bad.
Where is this Twilight Sparkle?
I'm looking forward
to meeting the competition!
Can't believe
I didn't recognize you earlier.
Should've known Princess Celestia would
send her prized pupil here after my crown.
And her little dog, too.
It's MY crown!
Whatever.
This is just a minor setback for me.
You don't know the first thing
about this place,
and I already rule it.
If that's so,
why do you even need my crown?
You went to an awful lot of trouble
to switch it with the one that belongs here.
Pop quiz:
what happens when you bring an
Element of Harmony into an alternate world?
You don't know? Seriously?
And you're supposed to be
Princess Celestia's star student?
Then again, what were the chances
she'd find somepony as bright as me
to take under her wing
after I decided to leave Equestria?
Bit embarrassing that you
were the best she could do.
Oh, and I'd keep an eye on your mutt.
Hate for him to be...
taken away from you.
Is that a threat?
Oh, of course not.
But I'd cut down on the chatter
if I were you.
Don't want everyone to know you two
don't belong here, now would you?
You want to be a princess here?
Please.
You don't know the first thing
about fitting in.
I want you to follow her.
Bring me something I can use
just like you did with that last girl
who thought she could challenge me.
You got it, Sunset Shimmer.
When the crown
and its power are mine,
Twilight Sparkle will be sorry
she ever set hoof into this world!
Not that she would've been much safer
if she'd stayed in Equestria.
Yeah, in Equestria.
What are you still doing here?!
Go!
Excuse me.
The Great and Powerful Trixie!
...Needs some peanut butter crackers.
Voilà!
Sunset Shimmer is right.
I don't know the first thing
about this place.
If I'm gonna really fit in
and win votes,
we need to do some research.
Research?
This place has a school.
I have to believe it's got a...
library!
Got your phone?
Got yours?
So I just push the letters here,
and then the words and moving
pictures will come up here?
That's right.
Maybe this place does have magic.
When you're a younger–
Girls! What are you doing?
We're just seeing how many hits
our new music video has gotten.
So the three of us
will fight the fight...
No, just...
No!
The school computers are
for research purposes only.
It's just as well, y'all.
Some of the comments about our song
were really awful.
"Epic Fail."
"Funniest thing I've ever seen"?!
Funniest thing they've ever seen,
huh?
Uh, I don't know that
that's what you should take from...
The library will be closing
in five minutes.
I hadn't even thought about
where we're going to sleep tonight!
Way ahead of you.
It's a little... dusty.
But it doesn't seem like
anybody comes up here
It's perfect, Spike.
- So, how did your research go?
- I found this book.
It's called a yearbook.
It seems to be something
they use to keep a record of things
that have happened at the school.
Look. That's Pinkie Pie,
Rainbow Dash, Applejack,
Fluttershy...
and I'm gonna bet
the girl on the far right is Rarity.
There's a Rarity here!?
Uh, I mean, uh... interesting photo.
It's interesting because
they look like they're friends.
They do look like our friends.
But I thought
we figured that out already.
No, I mean...
they look like they're friends
with each other.
But it doesn't seem like
they're friends now.
Not so much.
I just can't help but get the feeling
that Sunset Shimmer
had something to do with it.
I wouldn't put it past her.
But she wanted your crown
'cause she's planning on doing
something even worse!
If you're gonna stop her,
you have to focus
on making friends here.
Can't worry about why
these girls aren't friends anymore.
Even if they do remind you
of your Ponyville friends.
You're right, Spike.
Eye on the prize.
Good morning, students,
and happy Thursday.
Just a reminder to pick up your ballots
for the Princess of the Fall Formal today.
They are due at the time
the dance starts tomorrow night,
so don't forget to turn them in
and make your voice heard.
Fluttershy said I'd need to win over
all those different groups
if I want to become
Princess of the Fall Formal.
So I've compiled
a list of talking points.
You made a list?
That's so unlike you!
Uh... Please. Continue.
I'll start introducing myself.
Sprinkle in some things I've learned
about their world into the conversation.
Show them how I fit in here!
Okay, Spike.
Time to make a good first impression
on my fellow students.
The whole world
sort of depends on it.
Hey, look.
Why is everybody looking at me funny?
What're you...? Why did you...?
Rarity?
Oh, yes. This is good!
No one will recognize you!
Why wouldn't I want to be–
And we'll need a disguise for your dog.
Which is too bad.
He really is so adorable!
You know, with a little work,
I think I could make him
look like a rabbit instead.
A rabbit?
There you are, Twilight.
So much for the disguise.
I've been lookin' all over for ya!
- Me too.
- Me three!
I like your new look!
I do have an eye
for these sorts of things.
Not that you seem to care.
What?!
Why do you think she doesn't care?
No, never mind.
Why were you all looking for me?
What's going on?
She hasn't seen it yet.
Seen what?
Oh, it's really not that bad.
Twilight Sparkle wants to be
your Fall Formal Princess.
What does it say about our school
if we give someone like this...
such an important honor?
I take that back.
It's pretty bad!
But this all happened yesterday!
At the library!
Has everyone in the school seen this?
Is that why they were
all looking at me that way?
What am I gonna do?
No one is gonna vote for me
after seeing this!
Not that it'll make any difference,
but I'll still vote for you.
You were so nice to stand up for me
when Sunset Shimmer
was picking on me yesterday.
If you still wanna run, maybe
there's something I can do to help!
Word of advice?
Don't accept her help.
She doesn't take anything seriously!
Why do you have to be
so awful to me?
Don't play innocent, Pinkie Pie!
You are no better than she is!
And what is that supposed to mean?!
I am happy to offer up
my assistance as well.
To someone who would appreciate
what I have to offer!
Listen to y'all carryin' on!
Get over it and move on!
You mean like how you've gotten over
what happened with Rainbow Dash?
She said she'd get the softball team
to make an appearance at my bake sale.
I tell everybody they're comin',
and then not one of them shows up!
She made a liar outta me!
That's different!
Is not!
Is too!
STOP!
All of you!
I wanna show you something.
You were friends once.
The Freshman Fair.
- Y'all remember?
- Yes.
But something happened.
I think that something
was Sunset Shimmer.
Well, it's a nice theory, darling,
but Sunset Shimmer
had nothing to do with it.
She's right.
Sunset Shimmer isn't the one who ruined
my silent auction for the animal shelter
by bringing fireworks
and noisemakers!
It was supposed to be a serious event,
and Pinkie Pie ruined it!
What are you talking about?
I got a text from you saying
that you didn't want a silent auction.
You wanted a big party!
I never sent you a text!
You didn't?
You don't think she's the one who's
been sending me those e-mails, do you?
Every time I volunteer to help
with the decorations at a school function,
I get an e-mail from Pinkie Pie saying
she has plenty of volunteers!
And then I find out
she's done everything herself.
I never sent you any e-mails!
Maybe she's the reason Rainbow Dash
didn't show up for my bake sale!
Didn't you ever ask Rainbow Dash
why she didn't show up?
I guess I kinda stopped talking
to her at all after that.
Maybe now would be
a good time to start.
They're actually talking!
That's a good sign!
Hugs! Hugs are always good!
Somebody, and I think
we can all guess who,
told Rainbow Dash that my bake sale
had been moved to a different day.
Dash showed up with all the softball team
and thought I'd cancelled on her!
So you're looking
to dethrone Sunset Shimmer
and become
Princess of the Fall Formal, huh?
Gotta say, I'd really
love to see that happen.
I'll totally help you out!
All you gotta do...
is beat me in a game of one-on-one.
What?
First to five goals wins.
One-zip!
That's game!
I really thought you were gonna...
pull it off there in the end!
So what's the plan?
How can I help you be princess
instead of Sunset Shimmer?
But...
But... I...
But... I... lost!
Of course you lost. I'm awesome!
But I'm not gonna help just anybody
try and beat Sunset Shimmer.
The Fall Formal Princess should be
someone with heart and determination.
You've proved
that you've got 'em both!
And can I get mine with extra oats?
Oats?
Scratch that.
However you normally make it is fine.
We've got to stop bumping
into each other like this.
You know me!
Always trying to make
a big splash around here.
'Cause my drink kinda splashed...
on the ground!
I'm gonna go over there now.
Don't even think about it!
You're already trying to get her crown.
Who knows what Sunset Shimmer would do
if you ended up getting her ex-boyfriend too?
I'm not trying to. I don't even know...
We just accidentally...
Ex-boyfriend?
Flash Sentry broke up with her
a few weeks ago.
I can't believe she hasn't done
something awful to him yet.
Maybe she's just waiting until she has
the power to do something really awful.
All right, girls.
Dance is tomorrow night, and we still
don't know how we're gonna get Twilight
the votes she needs
to be named princess.
Right now, folks only know
the Twilight from the videos
Sunset Shimmer posted online.
We need to help them
see her differently.
I'VE GOT IT!
I mean, perhaps I have a solution.
Now this may be
an absolutely preposterous idea,
but what if we all wore these
as a sign of unity?
Freshman year, they were very,
very popular.
A way for everybody
to show their school spirit!
You know?
"Go, Canterlot Wondercolts!"
I haven't sold any in ages.
I mean, the five of us
are obviously very different,
but deep down,
we're all Canterlot Wondercolts!
Sunset Shimmer is the one
who divided us.
Twilight Sparkle is the one
who united us.
And we're gonna let everyone know it!
What do you think?
Hey! Hey! Everybody!
We've got something to say
We may seem as different
As the night is from day
But you look a little deeper,
and you will see
That I'm just like you
And you're just like me
Yeah!
Hey! Hey! Everybody!
We're here to shout
That the magic of friendship
Is what it's all about.
Yeah, we thought we were different
As the night is from the day
Until Twilight Sparkle
helped us see another way
So get up, get down
if you're gonna come around
We can work together
helping Twilight win the crown
So get up, get down
'Cause it's gonna make a sound
If we work together
Helping Twilight Sparkle
win the crown
Hey! Hey! Hands up now!
We're sending a message to the crowd!
Hands wave up, then come down
We party together all around!
Generous, honesty
Laughter, kindness, loyalty
Twilight helped us each to see
All that we can be
So get up, get down
If you're gonna come around
We can work together
helping Twilight win the crown
So get up, get down
'Cause it's gonna make a sound
If we work together
Helping Twilight Sparkle
win the crown
I'm gonna be myself
No matter what I do
And if we're different, yeah,
I want you to be true to you
If you follow me,
we'll put our differences aside
We'll stick together
and start working on that school pride!
Jump up, make a sound
Hey!
Stomp your hooves, turn around
Start now, make a change
Gonna come around
Jump up, make a sound
Hey!
Stomp your hooves, turn around
Canterlot Wondercolts,
help her win the crown
Jump up, make a sound
Hey!
Stomp your hooves, turn around
Start now, make a change
Gonna come around
Jump up, make a sound
Hey!
Stomp your hooves, turn around
Canterlot Wondercolts,
help her win the crown
Jump up, make a sound
Stomp your hooves, turn around
Start now, make a change
Gonna come around
Take those off!
I have something I need you to do.
Doesn't everyone look just fabulous?
It was a great idea, Rarity!
Don't know what she's smilin' about.
Twilight's the one that's gonna
be Princess of the Fall Formal.
Vice Principal Luna!
Something terrible has happened!
Isn't this just awful?
And after Pinkie Pie worked so hard
to make things so perfect!
Why would Twilight Sparkle
do something like this?
Why would you think Twilight
was responsible for something like this?
Because I have proof.
But... But I don't understand!
This is clearly you in the photographs.
Is it not?
Yes, but...
I think it should be fairly obvious
that the school cannot let someone
who would do something like this
compete for the Fall Formal crown.
Vice Principal Luna.
I found these in a trash can
in the library.
Thought you should see them.
Someone obviously combined these photos
to make it look like Twilight
was the one who trashed the gym.
I appreciate you bringing these
to my attention, Flash.
In light of this new evidence,
you may of course continue your bid
to be crowned
the Princess of the Fall Formal.
Thank you!
You have no idea how important
this is to me!
What was I gonna do?
Not prove your innocence?
Wouldn't be much of a
Canterlot Wondercolt, would I?
I am afraid enough damage
has been done to the gym
that we will have to postpone
the dance until tomorrow night.
If you will excuse me,
I need to let my sister know
about this latest development.
So, uh, I was wondering.
If you aren't already going
with somebody,
wanna go to the Fall Formal
with me tomorrow night?
That would be...
Tomorrow night!?
No, no no no no no, no no no no no!
Nonononono!
I can't! The portal!
That'll be too late!
One "no" would have been fine!
- Everything okay in there?
- Yes!
Only it's not okay.
It's not okay at all!
If I don't get my crown tonight,
I won't be able to go back to Equestria
for another thirty moons!
What are we gonna do?
We tell them the truth.
Let them know what's really at stake
if you don't get the crown tonight.
They'll help us figure something out.
But what if they won't?
What if when they find out
just how different I really am...?
Twilight, these girls rallied around you
'cause they saw what was in your heart.
They aren't going to feel
any differently about you
when they find out you're
pony princess in Equestria.
I'm glad you followed me here, Spike.
Me too.
Unless of course we get stuck here
for another thirty moons.
You okay?
The Fall Formal
isn't happening tonight.
WHAT!?
It had to be postponed
because Sunset Shimmer
had Snips and Snails
ruin all of Pinkie Pie's decorations.
WHAT!?
But the Fall Formal
has to happen tonight.
You see...
You're from an alternate world
and you're a pony princess there
and the crown actually has
a magical element embedded in it
that helps power up other magical elements,
and without it they don't work anymore
and you need them to help
protect your magical world,
and if you don't get the crown tonight,
you'll be stuck in this world
and you won't be able to get back for,
like, a really, really long time!
Yeah, I'm pretty sure
that isn't the reason.
Nope, she's pretty much spot-on.
He can talk!?
Oh, yeah!
And back where I come from,
I'm not even a dog!
I'm a ferocious,
fire-breathing dragon!
This is so amazing!
Tell me,
what are you thinking right now?
Sure would love a scratch
behind the old ears!
Uh, maybe later.
- How did you know all that?
- Just a hunch.
Wait a minute!
Let me get this straight.
You're a pony?
You're a princess?
You're from another world?
That... is...
awesome!
See? Told you.
I simply cannot believe
they did all this!
If I only had some kind of party cannon
that could decorate
everything super fast!
I know it seems impossible, but,
maybe if we all work together?
Now that's the kind of can-do spirit
I'm lookin' for in a Fall Formal Princess!
Let's do it, y'all!
- Absolutely!
- Rock on!
It's time for us to come together
It's the only way
that things will get better
It's time for us to take a stand
So come on and lend a helping hand
Fix it up,
yeah, it's all right
We'll get it ready by tonight
Mix it up,
yeah, help a friend
We'll come together in the end
It's time to show
that we've got school spirit
Raise your voice
and let everyone hear it
It's time to show that we're strong
So come on, everybody, sing along
Look how we've all come together
Things are only just
starting to get better
Look how we've all come together
Things are only gonna get better,
better, better, better!
Fix it up,
yeah, it's all right
We'll get it ready by tonight
Mix it up,
yeah, help a friend
We'll come together in the end
Fix it up,
yeah, it's all right
We'll get it ready by tonight
Mix it up,
yeah, help a friend
We'll come together, together now!
This... looks... sooooo... GOOD!
All right, everyone!
Fall Formal is back on
for this evening.
So you'd better get out of here
and start getting ready.
Oh, and don't forget to cast your ballots
for the Fall Formal Princess on your way out!
- You got my vote, Twilight.
- Mine, too!
- Mine too!
You're lucky she was able
to pull this off.
Next time I ask you
to make a mess of things,
try to show a little restraint!
I need this Formal to go on tonight
just as much as she does.
I still can't believe
we pulled that off!
I can! We're awesome!
Enough chatter, girls.
We need to get ready,
and we need to look fabulous!
This is our big night
We're getting ready,
and we're doing it up right
This is our big night
Friendship survived,
now we'll start it out right
The time's right, gonna make it last
'cause it's the first night
That we're ever gonna
start to just have fun together
We're so glad,
so happy we could never be mad
Did it right,
now this is our big night now
Six friends on the way up now
Six friends here to show you how
This is our big night
We're getting ready,
and we're doing it up right
This is our big night
We made it happen,
now let's party all night
This is our big night
Twilight !
Look, I know you said "no"
about going to the Fall Formal with me,
but would you reconsider
and at least have one dance?
I didn't say "no"!
I mean, I did, but...
I didn't mean no, to you.
I was... Well, what I mean is...
Yes. I'd love to dance with you!
Anybody seen Sunset Shimmer?
Maybe she was too embarrassed to show!
She's gotta know
you won by a landslide!
Maybe...
First off, I want to say how wonderful
everything looks tonight.
You all did a magnificent job
pulling things together
after the unfortunate events of earlier.
And now, without further ado,
I'd like to announce the winner
of this year's Fall Formal crown.
The Princess of this year's
Fall Formal is...
Twilight Sparkle!
Congratulations, Twilight.
Twilight! Help!
Spike?
They've got Spike!
That's close enough!
Twilight!
Don't hurt him!
Oh, I wouldn't dream of it.
I'm not a monster, Twilight.
Let him go.
You don't belong here.
Give me the crown,
and you can go back to Equestria tonight.
Or keep it and never go home.
Tick-tock, Twilight.
We haven't got all night.
The portal will be closing
on its own in less than an hour.
So, what's your answer?
- No.
- What!?
Equestria! Your friends!
Lost to you forever!
Don't you see what I'm about
to do to the portal?!
Yes,
but I've also seen what you've been
able to do here without magic.
Equestria will find a way to survive
without my Element of Harmony.
This place might not
if I allow it to fall into your hands.
So go ahead.
Destroy the portal.
You are not getting this crown!
Fine. You win.
You... are... so awesome!
I can't believe
you were gonna do that for us!
It's no wonder
you're a real live princess!
Oh, yes, she's so very special!
Grab him, you fools!
Spike, Spike!
Fluttershy!
I'll take that!
At last!
More power than I could ever imagine!
This is going to be so cool!
I've had to jump through so many hoops
tonight just to get my hands on this crown
and it really should
have been mine all along.
But let's let bygones be bygones.
I am your princess now.
And you will be loyal...
to me!
Round them up and bring them
to the portal.
Spoiler alert:
I was bluffing when I said
I was going to destroy the portal.
I don't want to rule
this pathetic little high school.
I want Equestria!
And with my own little
teenage army behind me,
I am going to get it!
No, you're not!
Oh, please!
What exactly do you think
you're going to do to stop me?
I have magic,
and you have nothing!
She has us!
Gee, the gang really
is all back together again.
Now step aside!
Twilight has tried to interfere with
my plans one too many times already!
She needs to be dealt with!
What!?
The magic contained in my Element
was able to unite with those
that helped create it!
Honesty!
Kindness!
Laughter!
Generosity!
Loyalty!
Magic
Together with a crown, they create a power
beyond anything you could imagine.
But it is a power you don't have
the ability to control!
The crown may be upon your head,
Sunset Shimmer,
but you cannot wield it.
Because you do not possess
the most powerful magic of all:
the magic of friendship!
What is happening?
Here and in Equestria,
it is the only magic
that can truly unite us all!
You will never rule in Equestria.
Any power you may have had
in this world is gone.
Tonight, you've shown everyone
who you really are.
You've shown them
what is in your heart.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I didn't know there was another way.
The magic of friendship
doesn't just exist in Equestria.
It's everywhere.
You can seek it out,
or you can forever be alone.
The choice is yours.
But all I've ever done since being here
is drive everyone apart.
I don't know the first thing
about friendship.
I bet they can teach you.
Those are my girls! Woo-hoo!
Did that dog just talk?
Whoa. Weird.
Seriously?
The talking dog is the weird thing
about all this?
I, for one, think you're adorable.
I believe this belongs to you.
A true princess in any world leads
not by forcing others to bow before her,
but by inspiring others
to stand with her.
We have all seen that
you are capable of just that.
I hope you see it too,
Princess Twilight.
I do.
Would now be a completely awkward time
to ask you for that dance?
This is our big night
We made it happen,
now let's party all night
We're here now and we worked
so hard to make it come around
To tonight so let's try
to make it last forever
The school lights so bright,
beat is pumping through the night
Party's starting,
DJ's got the music just right!
Six friends on the way up now
Six friends here to show you how
This is our big night
You'll look out for her,
won't you?
Of course we will.
Although I do expect some sort of apology
for last spring's debacle.
I have a feeling she'll be
handing out a lot of apologies.
We better get going.
I know we've only been friends
for a short time,
but I'm gonna miss all of you so much.
That crown really does suit you...
Princess Twilight.
You know what, Spike?
I am starting to feel a little
more comfortable wearing it.
And the wings?
I've been walking on two legs
and picking things up with these!
Wings?
I'm thrilled that's all I'll be
dealing with back in Equestria!
Bummer!
Twilight!
- Ah, you're back!
- You got your crown!
I knew you could do it!
Oh, we were so worried.
Sunset Shimmer, is she alright?
I think she's going to be fine.
I left her in good hands.
What are hands?
- Where did you stay?
- What did they wear?
- Did you have fun?
- What'd you eat?
Would you say she's just
as awesome as me?
I want to tell you
all everything, I do,
but I'm just so exhausted
from all the dancing.
Dancing?
We've got to stop bumping
into each other like this.
Who was that?
He's a new member of the castle guard.
Flash Sentry, I think.
Why? Do you know him?
Not exactly.
Somepony's got a crush
on the new guy!
No. No, I don't.
She does! She absolutely does!
Don't be ridiculous.
I don't even know him.
He just...
Totally reminds you of a guy you met in the
other world who played guitar, was in a band
and helped prove you didn't destroy
all the decorations for a big dance,
so you could still run
for princess of the big dance,
and then asked you
to dance at that dance!
Right?
How did you know that?
Just a hunch!
A friend for life,
that's what you are to me
I couldn't see what was
right there in front of me
Turned my back
and my mind off track, yeah
You saw a world,
there was something new entirely
Helped me to see
all the possibilities
Oh, like a star in the daylight,
or like a diamond at night
Your light was hidden
from my sight
A friend for life,
that's what you are to me
Every friendship is tested
You say you're sincere
but it's all unclear now
But with a word,
everything changes
And just like that,
you and I are right back
Oh, like a star in the daylight,
or like a diamond at night
The light will shine
when the time is right
A friend for life,
that's what you are to me
When I put my hand out
and I thought I would fall
You knew what I needed
and you came around to fix it all
A friend for life,
that's what you are to me
That's what you are to me